Wildan Akbar Putra Nugraha

I'm as an IT Product Designer and UI/UX Designer with over 6 years of dedicated experience in crafting user-centric solutions.

My journey in design began in 2016 as a Website Designer, and now my specialize in IT Product Design, UI/UX Design, Interaction Design, and UX Research. check thisout to my portfolio website: www.wildanakpn.xyz

Work Experience

Freelance IT Product Designer UI/UX Designer

Nov 2018 - Present

Nov 2018 - Present | Remote

- Leveraged user research (end-to-end, user-market fit) and design expertise (wireframing, high-fidelity mockups, prototyping) to deliver impactful IT product solutions for global and local clients.
- Enhanced existing websites and applications for individual and corporate clients, ensuring user-centricity and alignment with business goals.
- Conducted comprehensive user research and leveraged design expertise to create user-centric IT products.
- Enhanced existing websites and applications, ensuring alignment with business goals and user preferences.
- Possessed early-stage programming knowledge for efficient collaboration with developers.

Junior Frontend and Web Designer at PT. Sale Stock Indonesia

Jan 2016 - Dec 2017

Jan 2016 - Dec 2017 | Yogyakarta, Indonesia | Full-time | On-site

- At that time it was the first time I was acquainted with the world of software designers, and my main task at that time was to become a website designer who works using Adobe XD and always works using the principles of Software Development Live Cycle to always make improvements and updates on our retail fashion ecommerce platform website at that time.
- Designed and developed user-centric interfaces for websites and mobile applications using Adobe XD.
- Worked with Software Development Life Cycle principles to continually improve and update the e-commerce fashion retail platform.
- Enhanced skills in web development, user experience design, and front-end development.

Project

Redesign Blu BCA Mobile Banking App Redesign to add New Feature's Shopee Mobile App Revamping Home Page on Leverate Group Website	7 7 7		
		Revamping Facebook Marketplace on Facebook App	7
		F1 (*	

Education

California Institute of the Arts

Associate's degree UI / UX Design Specialization

University of Maryland

Associate's degree Specialization Product Ideation Design

University of Colorado

Associate's degree Secure Sofware Design Specialization

Contact

Phone: +62 857 2980 0632
Email: wildanakpn@gmail.com
Website: www.wildanakpn.xyz
Medium: medium.com/@wildanakpn

Skills

 User Research (End-to-End, User-Market Fit)

Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/wildanakpn

- Design (Wireframing, High-Fidelity Mockups, Prototyping)
- UI Design
- · UX Design
- Web Design, Responsive Web Design
- Mobile Application Design
- Web Development (HTML, CSS, Javascript)
- · Design Thinking
- Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC)
- · Proactive Problem Solving
- Collaboration, Product Management

Tools

- Design Tools: Figma, Adobe XD, Lunacy, Penpot.
- Prototyping Tools: InVision, Marvel, Axure, Proto.io, Figma.
- **Graphic Tools**: Adobe Illustrator, CorelDraw, Adobe Photoshop,
- Video Tools: Adobe Premiere
 Pro, Adobe After Effects, Capcut
- Code Editor: VS Code, idx.

Certification

- <u>Principles of UX/UI Design</u> From Meta
- <u>Designing User Interfaces and</u>
 <u>Experiences (UI/UX) From IBM</u>
- Enterprise Design Thinking Practitioner From IBM
- Enterprise Design Thinking Co-Creator From IBM
- Enterprise Design Thinking -Team Essentials From IBM
- <u>Build Dynamic User Interfaces</u> (UI) for Websites From Google
- <u>UX Design Process: Empathize,</u>
 <u>Define, and Ideate From Google</u>
- Google UX Design Specialization From Google
- Gold UI/UX Design Mastery
 From Skilvul